this beautiful Tuesday morning charged
watch so you mean what I would really do
with this thing I really don't know it's
dead to better I had a little display of
wearables that I bought that nobody
would ever use good morning convict okay
so let me tell you why I haven't been on
to it for a bit because we've been out
of Montague but today we have green mata
your bhumata enlightenment this is the
best one though I used to think that I'm
having it now I took two sips it's kind
of mediocre you know what I want
twitchy's waffles get me waffles no I
don't know about any waffles but all
right so let's see what music we listen
to today and then we'll get to it and
we'll get to working
yeah I listen to this song
[Music]
yes early brothers put a job you know so
you gotta come here before your job
[Music]
that's how I feel about San Francisco
you know whenever the other person here
once every other to leave that's right
San Francisco was truly a tribal city
guys it's home to different factions of
people who all want different things and
all dislike the other factions we have
our very own set of Morlocks there's no
the Morlocks who read the time traveler
tie the time machine knows that that's
cool
hey let's go what do we want to do well
focus on this for the optivisor off the
optimize are awful we'll just we'll fix
all the vertices and then let's focus on
removing the low-quality points
look at all these low quality points
those shouldn't exist
I eventually go away I think I think my
pruner eventually works but like it'll
work a lot better if we could just not
add them all that crap all right so
let's read let's read orbs then stopped
all right so what we do we do like this
filtering here but let's see what works
I know they're gonna work so I'm just
has like really fancy hashtag for this
here we go
triangulate each map sub new girl cruise
mission hanging out with that girl
tonight you know they still hang out
okay check parallax between rays let's
figure out that means links in your
clinic paper you guys know what parallax
between rays means
seneschal matches the fulfill at the
bowler constraint so that's search for
triangulation so that's search by
projection I think well this is a search
by projection as points that are already
on the map so this is about adding new
points
let's find the point in 25% new mappoint
creation connected key frames for each
unmapped new map points are created by
triangulating or from connected key
frames in the co visibility graph for
each unmatched orb and ki we search a
match with the other unmatched point in
the other key frame I describe those
matters that do not fulfill the epipolar
constraints or pairs of triangulate and
to accept the new points positive depth
in both cameras parallax reproduction
error and scale consistency are checked
initially a map point is observed from
two key frames so that it could be
matched in others ok so yeah guys I like
Microsoft I don't have a problem with
Microsoft they've never done anything to
like really piss me off I tell you I
probably like them better than like
Google I don't know yeah I'm really just
like Google either but like
fundamentally Microsoft's business model
is much more aligned with my goals than
like Google's business model I think
it's unfortunate that like Google and
Facebook of media companies talk about
this a little on Twitter it's some face
it's unfortunate that their media
companies right because the media
company does not have the same goals as
you where is a company like Microsoft or
Apple I mean they kind of just wanna
like you don't like sell your product
right like they want to sell your
product or service that's fine that's
like the engine of capitalism that's
what makes capitalism great but really I
mean capitalism when it's based on
consent I mean that is consent right
when I go when I purchase an iPhone axis
is a consensual transaction between me
and app
when Google you know tracks my cookie
around the internet and then like uses
psychology to figure out what's most
likely to get me to click on an ad it's
not so consensual anymore right
no just wanting money is great guys
though don't don't don't get it twisted
like capitalism and wanting money is
great um the problem is like you know
they it's a sec if you Oh God
we won't go there we won't go there
that's too much but like you really what
it comes down to his consent okay ah yes
when she'll close estimation new
mappoint creation but we check for
positive depth in both cameras parallax
reprojection error if I recall correctly
orb slim just does the triangulation in
yeah it's just doing in the real world
it's just doing it in like full-on
keyframe
so we had this for a bit but I didn't
think it worked
all right this trip just just doing it
in the actual pose of the frame but when
I try this it didn't work
I had like numerical stability issues
I'm not very good Martha um no
capitalism's always consent it's like
advertising they can kind of blared a
line right know what is advertising but
what kind of a form of coercion you know
you don't want coercion pretend oh okay
I think I actually know the reason it
broke ah this is interesting okay I
think that it's just because my 0.1
check was bad
did I break the google chrome sandbox I
don't talk about that okay
translate the point we don't have
matches for so for some reason doesn't
stop triangulating the mall we don't
really have to do that I don't do we
and then we don't
so they just say equals equals 0 which
is ballsy talk to a reporter later today
you know you gotta I gotta gonna say
nice things to the reporter
you know nobody close in assembly
language don't be don't be a new noobs
lot of noobs ok I'm gonna really show
what that does
okay now we're separating triangulation
from the checks okay now let's do checks
down here so we check that a
triangulates in front of the camera so
basically what we want to do I believe
like you really see this well on the
kitty reverse one I want to
[Music]
so if you dotted with the inverse of the
pose and projected from the local frame
into the global frame which makes me
think that if u dot it with the hose
itself
is that the same thing like I don't know
why they look at all the complicate the
right why is there all this complex
[Music]
that that that I don't like why is that
that's just wrong
sicut math bros okay so that's not like
right RCW row 2 . so they're really only
computing the Z that's just just say
compute couldn't care less
small right
it seems more right okay so we have to
check that it's in front of both cameras
so you can see like this point here is
behind the cam as well so let's just
think this through and think whether I'm
doing this right so we're moving forward
so we're moving forward on the z axis
so we would expect that the points were
moved into local camera frame or if
we're at 6 and this is zero no hacking
anyone talks about hackings band things
illegal bros don't have all right so
this is 0 this is 6 so we would expect
that if the point is at 66 in global
coordinate frame it's not like 60 a
little corner frame so this is correct
right
so I don't know why but that's correct
well so this is it whoops there's a CV
to camera thing that I really like it's
just shows you could wait think about it
trim zips this yet so that's our pose
matrix and we're dotting our pose matrix
with the okay so you see what luckily
does suppose matrix and we dot it with
that
um so we end up with will say you know
the one the L so if PL 1 sub 2 is less
than 0 or PL 2 sub 0 is less than 0
check points there's I don't like this
equals 0 here when do things equal 0 and
I'm sure what that means in a flowing
point world it's got a little really
identical it equals 0
okay it was like somewhat less crap
okay check reprojection error in first
keyframe check reprojection are in
second keyframe okay I don't know why
they wrote this like ridiculously
complex and I should just be able
to take that point I'm immersed I might
just take that point and I can go like
this I move this out of the main class
throw get out of hacking hacking sore
losers that's cool boss math do math
that's cool
very cool so those are the X&Y points
now we can actually test the
reprojection our vehicle so those are
the errors in the reprojection if we
assume that that's the point so we can
check them they look reasonable oh I
don't know what it allowed error should
be
five nine nine 106 I'm not using me and
square they're just using I just mean
squared they're just not taking the
square root 5 point 9 9 1 times Sigma
square one ok no no
this one's seven greater than one want
to say about hacking equals BAM wants to
be banned
okay I think the last check I need to
write is the parallax check would be
helpful if I understood with parallax
what's so big good subtle there's always
some sucker that will buy the machine
learning is not limited by data summary
by infrastructure okay let's let's check
parallax check reprojection air check
scale consistency know what that means I
think we have that oh you wouldn't we
don't have scale talk about on the
Hellmouth kind of cool it's not
self-driving cars
we're really going to talk about slam
okay check parallax between race let's
understand this in FX I don't understand
what the stuff is Oh
okay so this is just dotting it with kN
I think I have already so we can take
yes I'm gonna check that we'll check
that up top oh let's in helpers just
check this for all
cool
this kind of summer house I don't
know if that transpose is really okay
that probably is yeah it's like a fairly
symmetrical matrix okay so that's just
projecting them into normal frame so let
me see what this parallax check actually
means check parallels between race okay
well so that's X and one they call it X
n 1 and xn to copy their naming
convention I don't really know what that
means but our wc1 so it's the rotation
of the key frame
I don't really understand this no stereo
and very low parallax no first off
that's a bug guys you should be checking
for my bugs okay
so we want to this is a rotation based
on the polls for the coffee there is
exactly I'm not really understand what
it does it's this ray 1 dot ray to
I don't banish Tanis
why are they rotating Oh kind of get it
parallax is large okay so ray one dot
right - exactly I already checked our
relaxants large enough so oh they're
doing Excel one yeah oh that's kind of
you
I do that with triangle right I don't
what has work
oh so just don't do it with KP use okay
this is this is stupid
we don't actually need to dot these K
ends because we actually track that
already Oh
so we're might have had backwards after
do so by dxi if you update your readme
section and Lib CB to this leads why I
don't think it matters so called CB - oh
no if it's open CV it's not over TV -
ready - course TV too long I feel great
for 2 - 3 1 4 3 2 right okay so there
dotting them together and dividing it by
the noir
this is apparently never paralyzed this
only is one this might only be like not
close to one in the presence of crazy
rotation or something this does seem
like the most useless metric or I did
the math wrong
it's like always 1/cosine parallax raise
is less than
who's listening close up Alex staring no
so we don't even have a cosine phallic
stare because there is no stereo the
is this B stereo one B stereo
2 and cosine power x-rays is less than
point 9 9 9 8 see what we get lost a lot
of points
cuz the crap going that's what matters
no we still crap we more crap
should I get the check backwards
104 hi parallax points have a definition
someone if seen is planar or nearly
planar and there's little tie rods to be
explained with a homography
parallax is checked okay so basically
yeah points at infinity do not have mm
sufficient parallax ourselves not
including the map in a variant form of
those - a cameo shot
huh parallax now so they did definitely
the other way
the other Shack you understand like most
of the time this thing doesn't have
stereo close parallax stereo equals
Coast parallax raise plus one and these
stereos you'll be sure to or customize
so that's gonna check that matters I
don't know like it just looks like it
throws a lot of points away I'll show
about the ground truth and see if that
works
we're just throwing a lot of points away
when we do this well that looks better
well that looks significantly better
take a look look at look at how it's not
like you know that's so much smoother
wait except for the fact that it's so
smooth that is just flying off the end
okay so actually it becomes under
because it's totally wrong so
this check is garbage
wait zero vertices to optimize cuz I'm
not applying to the frame okay
different problem bros put that back to
okay so now we have we have jerkiness
this is with without the parallax check
this vaguely correct set the power I
don't know looks kind of the same the
same kind of low quality she'll get a
low quality the map might be higher
quality and I think we might be getting
less crap but are we just getting less
crap because like
we're adding less things oh I love money
guys I love money money is great money
is you should want money money is what
makes the world go round
love money love capitalism money some
people don't have money yeah yeah that's
the tragedy man but I got money
I love button you should love money -
that's right
let's see let's look at some money oh
yeah look at this
$20 yeah bros look at that money ha ha
ha I love money my monitors dirty don't
talk about hacking we're not talking
about hacking bros i'm talking about
slam that's right and money they're
talking about money
that's right $20 yeah get it get all
this crap being added to my mouth look
at all my crap I thought that went over
there oh I hate this check understand
what raise our man that's all right
the other checks are all very reasonable
boys toys
- for my reproduction army pushing up
this - - let's be a little more
reasonable
how can you have money don't know earn
it perform a valuable service for your
fellow member of society
Titano fancy v3 is not it's wrong that's
wrong like not having money have money
problematic nature
oh this push
no no murderer those belong there no
that's never gonna match up those points
oh my math is ruined
you're our money from computer your
money from computer there's so many
opportunity our money
look at that
look at it it doesn't really do that I
do this one doesn't do that well why do
cuz it's not office optimizing but like
updating normal and depth we should
probably track normals as well it might
be a cool thing to do what do you think
about working no no no no no no no no no
that might give you money but what you
really want is passive income
just imagine the problem with working
for Google or a big company to have
money is you have to work imagine you
found a way where you could just get
money you know what I'm saying like you
don't have to do anything
you just get money what a deal that
would be all right let's let's change
this all bro work is life you think you
wanna do you work for somebody else man
gonna get equity you got to work for
yourself you spend your life making the
salary let me tell you something you're
never gonna be rich you're always gonna
be working you gotta you gotta get some
money you know maybe maybe put that
in the stock market bro figure out how
to invest and don't want that some dumb
invest an index funds that's right
if you invest in index funds invest in
in you know what PewDiePie's has invest
in property bros if lam ex top shape one
just want to add a 1 to the end I know
it's terrible
I don't want more viewers I like having
a few of you bros if I have too many
viewers it would turn into a
lowest-common-denominator trash like our
education system in if you sucked it
next one's great
oh you don't have money to start the
work well that sounds like a
bootstrapping problem and I don't know
how to fix that that's you have to be
born into money it's
man I don't know where you're from this
is America and America is greatest land
the land of opportunity and there's so
much opportunity you can like pick up a
rock in America and there's opportunity
underneath it probably no man digging
took time series model I don't know yeah
I mean the trick to getting rich is okay
step 1 find somebody who has money
step 2 convinced them to give you that
money but don't do this in a scummy way
don't don't like be a creep about it you
know what I mean I mean you could
probably talk about the same two steps
to getting laid but you know like don't
be creepy about it man like don't be
like sketchy about like how you make
your money make your money like a honest
way you know oh yo yo I do love Taylor
Swift that's right
that's very cool Taylor smoke I don't
know though I don't think I'd actually
really get along with tell us whipped
yeah we should commit this is pretty
good
here's that all right with a local
window again fixed up that we use that
ones we get the translation global frame
you have a commented out check for
parallax change what's my time at the
lips of Selena Gomez I'm not much about
Selena Gomez guys I just know that that
come and get it na na na song was about
Justin Bieber being afraid to lose his
virginity
what's Mack do I have like what like the
most expensive MacBook Pro you can buy
at the store not like special order cuz
that's too much but I go to store like
the highest end MacBook Pro that you
guys sell because I'm rich and you
should aspire to be rich and you should
aspire to make money because let me tell
you something if you're making money
you're contributing in a positive way to
society and that's what it's all about
guys that's what it's all about doing
services and goods for your fellow man
talk about guys no politics stay out of
politics press politics is mine killer
you know let me tell you something like
every time people read these
political articles new look oh my god
this is happening this is happening I'm
like I don't give a man though I am
excited about about peace with North
Korea
cuz we love peace peace is great we
could be friends
I'd like to just see North Korea like I
kind of want to be one of those like oh
no like I'm a friend who went um I kind
of like to be able to those people like
goes like maybe right when it like
collapses yeah Bill Gates I mean yeah
right you know it's a god you know what
I didn't like the Bill Gates said though
taxing robots as dumb as
Bill Gates calls for robot tax no no no
that's so dumb I don't like taxes but
not a political way you know like I'm
not gonna like campaign about it I'm
just gonna like mildly complain while I
pay my taxes cuz that's what you do in
America you know they say that there's
two things in life you can't avoid the
taxes a death
I'm okay with pay taxes I would like to
avoid the death though I think maybe may
if we all work hard you know we could
avoid that good so this is good that
this works because it didn't work before
when I did it in a global frame but it
was because that sounds like politics I
also asked the question of where did you
hear that from did you see it in person
like if you saw it in person than the I
trust you're feeling pretty up
alike time series model is two steps to
get late
no no getting late is like getting money
just convince someone you know you find
someone who has that and then you you
you know you do you've convinced them in
a positive way no coercion to uh you
know to share it with you right now
that's the same thing with money it's
all the same for us what do you
think about break Bitcoin code and be
rich is that a positive impact on
society that's
the question you have to ask yourself
it's not just like if you just like be
rich and you're a dick don't do that be
rich and have a positive impact on
society I wanna press so okay how good
that looks until like it doesn't look
good anymore me you from this angle
doesn't look as good what is all this
that shows up well it's like
speckle does a rotation one more like
that one doesn't work at all worked a
little bit if I had to relax check it
it'll work
oh it's kind of better with the parallax
check
well okay so part of the problem too is
we got rid of the kinematic model give
this aura true
then we just get this kind of behavior
which this actually is not the ground
troops for the thing as far as I can
tell yeah kinematic models crap oh no no
it's always other individuals there's
only individuals bros all we have is
individuals in the world everybody let
me tell you something you're born an
individual
you'll die an individual and whenever
people try to talk about how it's for
the common good
like oh oh do it for the common good I
mean that's just like that's just the
way of saying me but they're trying to
be more like politically correct about
it right
like like you should you should fund
this project for the people and they'd
like you look at the person who's saying
that you like but isn't that like you
our project
aren't you gonna like make a lot of
money no no it's for the people don't do
that don't be one of those people be
like yes it's for me and I will get rich
but you will benefit as well and then
everybody wins right like don't be one
of those like you know what I'm saying
do we know until we can talk about Elon
Musk you know must is a bro man we love
you on musk you are musk is doing so
much good for society Elon Musk is gonna
get me into space now let me tell you
about space look I love space but like I
don't want to go to space until it's
nice but what's greatest is there's all
these people in the world who want to go
to space even when it's not nice and
they're gonna make space nice and then
I'll go to space when it's nice am i a
better programmer in the law boskie
right now
okay so the optimizer just messes
everything like that
Sigma Chi default 11 great what does it
do that space have different gravity and
I've heard this yeah or watch out for
space gravity why is this seg faulting
what seg faults I don't understand but
they're Nan's going into the optimizer
their names going into the optimizer
known as
what segfault think I understand okay
okay yeah I know I know what quit on
expect yourself I don't even have gdb on
this computer I only have L LD be make
space nicer again that's what I'm
talking about man I want to go to like
man intercontinental space ritz-carlton
space Mandarin Oriental space I want to
cover an oriental space but don't be
poor because if you're poor they won't
let you go to the Mandarin Oriental
space gotta be rich at this point look
it's so far away far away that point is
so far away points practically you look
at this point
please practically in space I think
about quantum I think it's full of
scammers man I don't know I think that P
equals B Q P P equals b QP now I'm sure
someone's gonna link me to the blog post
says showing me that is a bright oh I
know why it's seg faulting now that's a
stupid reason
it's like volts when it can't move any
frames for some reason
like the problem is when you have almost
purely rotational movement of a camera
you don't really get you don't get depth
information of the points so you can't
make a good map
one of you guys at Mars this is what I'm
talking about they gotta make a right
shop on Mars first though cuz I don't
wanna grow my own rice that sounds hard
what's my comment about NASA vs. SpaceX
what do you mean why has it vs. bro
anyone who wants to go to space is cool
NASA can go space space I can go to
space you know it's really cool about
space is really big there's plenty of
room and space for everybody
maybe we don't have to like be Dixon
like fight over space maybe we could
just be like you could have this space
that I could have this space and damn
there's so much space I would love to
see humanity colonize all space matches
all of space imagine this like space
McDonald's man when are they gonna build
the first McDonald's in another galaxy
when I get many simpler videos that
serve as a test case instead of just
watching this one all the time yeah I
mean that's kind of sense of all I
should probably do that probably get
more test cases well so a few things I
want to do use the alt optimizer
the alt optimizer better
we could get many simpler videos I mean
that's okay so that's one direction we
go in this is we talk kinda smooth this
is somebody could get a dot product to
map I don't know what that is so part of
the problem with other videos well
there's other Fryeburg videos let's
download another Fryeburg video
this one looks cool
Wow des
phishing online surface correction for
large Wow looks pretty nice
so they're using depth info though okay
so those are for testing and debugging
the law
desk desk - room room that sounds good
let's get room
why call she/he no no no no no no no no
there's only gonna be beautiful women on
Mars that's what they promised me man
have you ever read any be comic about
space that's right no I don't know about
that man I think there's better things
to do what Mars to be honest like eat
rice all right this is downloading you
guys can't see it down low because I'm
covering it what's F R 1 and F R 2 I
don't even know but this is a rolling
shutter camera what a scam
this is rolling shutter cabba see what
like a LSD slam you know what I can
actually they talked about this in the
water sign paper don't I what data sets
they test them on I so this is Kitty you
test a lot on kitty
which Kitty is this because some of the
kiddies are better than other kitties
they're also doing a loop closure which
I'm not writing the closure they didn't
use room I didn't see the music room
that accuracy though they use desk
you know what let's just write a proper
I did this in one of my previous go oh
man you know we should pack I think my
APM is kind of low man
did you get my AVM up you know copy and
paste this and just we'll stick it on
the parcel
and ground truth timing is not txt yeah
that's our DB dot txt just index out of
range of you save it as - now we have
the room room our room looks nice so why
is my slam so crappy I think it would
make like a nice map okay don't get
kolmad failures last my slam so crappy
these points are crappy
okay that's arguably less crappy Wow
but it's still not it's not crispy
okay so one of the things that orb slam
is doing to the mouse on tea mugs all
the guys they'll still that's gross
one of the things orb slim does that I'm
not doing is orbs I'm uses key frames I
am putting every frame into the
optimizer which mean you think like more
informations better right but that might
not necessarily be true
that's pretty nice hey bro Staggs a nice
map
let's get rid of the ground truth don't
see how crappy it is now
so we're not using that constant
velocity model we're using crappy seats
like messed up oh no we got an infinite
Jack hate that infinite Jack yes so the
problem is right now that it always
assumes motion cuz that's how the and
what we could do is we could rescale it
so let's say yeah hang on the initial
position for fundamental matrix if frame
ID greater than five philosophy here say
velocity velocity right now it's like
it's crazy like close like
not so strong that is now gonna print
out yeah so you see that's like a
velocity so actually scale it based on
that now we can say x that's a little
better right now it stops alright good
it doesn't bug a bunch nah nah nah no
okay well it just goes crazy now this
magnitude goes crazy because it
shouldn't dammit it feeds back on itself
no okay this was the crappy idea don't
do this
stupid or clip actually just use as a
kinematic model like this and those are
gonna works
I use a kinematic model I end up with
des Oh Oh mods
yeah so if it loses translation it
doesn't recover translation this is a
problem in orange slim as well money is
kind of dirty that's true
I wouldn't like a money problem with the
fundamental matrix though is like it
doesn't scale though if you don't have a
translation component that's very large
it doesn't scale it well
[Music]
well it survived longer now what about
OpenCV buck with Alex nice it's a crispy
pie on a map
I don't know how it jumped over there
that's not what's doing it all look how
it's like broken why is it so crappy
there's part of the maps kind of nice
stop being crappy what two genomes to be
famous that just go do something
gotta get that discipline the best true
you do need discipline in life
okay well that didn't work
God why is the word slam so much better
actually I'd never actually seen or slim
around on room so maybe it doesn't work
this is a ground truth
Taron ground tree help set
it doesn't cheolma like crazy anymore
those are all wrong
so much peace
but my math doesn't look crisp
yeah else no I can only do that we do
run the pose optimizer at every frame
right I don't know we don't cuz we have
ground rates of cost so we're just
staying in it
keeps jumping in there that's why we
oppose this fix yourself slam something
look a sapper I look at that bro
yes stand still bro if you're a moving
object you're bad look at that bro stand
still
he's famous she's in Freiburg oh my god
you literally pass right by a white wall
that's unusable
yes that's why nobody succeeds at room
nobody uses room tell it one more than
obviously muses desk and floor it's down
a desk
desk
so there's also death information we
could potentially use but that's kind of
cheating and notice how they don't use
so notice how they only use XYZ they
don't use notation because I don't think
it can do it we know we're slim succeeds
at floor and desk and XYZ
see our desk looks
okay like but even like look like this
is all messed up like this is the same
this is ghosting it's the same thing
twice alright those points are all
garbage okay we know orb slam does
almost perfectly on desk
the real problem is cuz my crappy uh do
we need key frames set the problem which
one talks briefly about why they use key
frames bundle adjustments
care about real-time
so I'm was initially everyone's process
shortly so in the Matthew Legation yeah
okay so this the accumulation of
linearization errors I don't really
understand what that means because that
would involve like math but like I've
heard the same crap with Kalman filters
- okay I mean this is a great video to
test on like you can really test almost
everything in this video but let's try
so that's just doing it with less frames
energy seems to kind of work better
the map is crispier
know all that just not stuff like you
can't see what oh you can't say oh you
can't read the text oh sorry yeah okay
I've got today's work on slim tomorrow
to do but yes so that's what we will do
tomorrow
the idea of keyframes is instead of
putting every frame and the optimizer
you only put some in the optimizer
there's linearization errors I think is
what's happening now and I think that's
why it works limbs a lot better than us
still so we will look into that uh
tomorrow I'll see you twitch is tomorrow
it is 9:00 in the morning welcome
welcome good morning Vietnam we were
asked to peace travel lamps that's it
all right
see you later